<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-16T23:14:32-07:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mechanical Flight</title><subtitle>The headspace of Gregory J. McClure.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Antiode to the Heart</title><link href="/poems/2014/04/05/antiode-to-the-heart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Antiode to the Heart" /><published>2014-04-05T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-04-05T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/poems/2014/04/05/antiode-to-the-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="/poems/2014/04/05/antiode-to-the-heart.html">&lt;p&gt;My own is the telegraph of another’s&lt;br /&gt;
will, the living text of foreign desire,&lt;br /&gt;
copying news only ever copied&lt;br /&gt;
imperfectly, original to no one,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but given again a palled night long past.&lt;br /&gt;
I am suspicious of the thing. It works&lt;br /&gt;
in me, not by request, my ruling rhythm&lt;br /&gt;
always to a beat I can’t subdue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t stop it, I can’t make it louder,&lt;br /&gt;
can’t teach it to love you if it won’t —&lt;br /&gt;
this pulsing mass, unwanted Quasimodo&lt;br /&gt;
abandoned on the doorsteps of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let it die. What’s shared in our silences&lt;br /&gt;
can be refined in our figuring — try&lt;br /&gt;
any new star, for example: traces&lt;br /&gt;
of dust in space, intending of themselves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to be apart, find in their shared disdain&lt;br /&gt;
a trust, and, pressing close, begin to burn.&lt;br /&gt;
We’re born of what is made within this rending.&lt;br /&gt;
It isn’t love that is unending.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My own is the telegraph of another&amp;#8217;s will, the living text of foreign desire, copying news only ever copied imperfectly, original to no&amp;nbsp;one &amp;hellip;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two-Wolf Variations</title><link href="/prose/2013/06/01/two-wolf-variations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two-Wolf Variations" /><published>2013-06-01T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-06-01T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/prose/2013/06/01/two-wolf-variations</id><content type="html" xml:base="/prose/2013/06/01/two-wolf-variations.html">&lt;p&gt;“A fight is raging inside me,” said an old man to his son. “It
is a terrible fight between two wolves. One wolf is darkness, rage,
grief. The other is good: compassion, peace, and love. The same fight is
going on inside you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The son considered this carefully for a moment and then asked, “Which
wolf will win?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man replied simply, “The one you feed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The son thought this over again and, recalling some things he’d learned
in his health class recently, he said to his father, “What if I feed the
evil wolf a gluten-free diet of organically raised, garden-green produce
and sustainably farmed white-protein sources, and the good wolf a more
mainstream diet of fatty red proteins and GMO-based corn
products, maybe some occasional fast-food runs?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the old man had fallen asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I would seriously kill for some McD’s,” the boy thought. He
watched the old man sleep for a minute, regarding him fondly. Then he
yoinked a five-spot from the old man’s wallet and stole into the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A fight is going on inside me,” said an old man to his son.
“It’s a terrible fight involving three wolves. One wolf is darkness,
rage, grief. Another is good, compassion, peace. The third wolf sits at
a distance, observing the battle and refusing to judge either one. The
same wolves are within you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The son considered this carefully for a minute and then said, “Okay —
so the third wolf neither wins nor loses? He just judges and stumbles
around in his boxers?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” the old man said, “but if he does, he doesn’t
give a fuck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right,” the son continued, “so, you’re, what? The third wolf?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I never said any damned thing about —”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think I get it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fuck you,” the old man said. “You don’t get shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I get that you’re never sober,” the son shot back, and the old
man whirled, squared off, paws bunched into white fists. He
hesitated —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“WHAT?” the son yelled. “You don’t have THE GUTS? TRY IT!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The father seethed: “Go find your mother and ask her if I had the guts
twenty years ago! ASK HER!” Then the old man winced
and beat his chest, and the boy, nearly in tears even though he’d seen
this a hundred times before, stormed away, wondering when he’d get his
chance for one shot, just one fair shot at that used-up son of a bitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A fight is going on inside me,” said an old man to his son.
“It is a terrible fight involving two wolves. One wolf is your Aunt
Imelda’s spicy tuna-broccoli casserole, and the other wolf is your Uncle
Jeff’s incessant bullshit about the ‘problems with this country.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The son wasn’t sure about what to say, but the old man kept staring at
him with what might have been a tinge of annoyance, even anger, though
the boy couldn’t guess at what. Finally, the son said, “Which wolf is
going to win?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man shut his eyes and shook his head. “Your uncle’s stupidity
isn’t going away anytime soon, but I think that casserole is about to
herald its triumphant spiritual return.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that, the father let rip a loud “howl,” and then belched explosively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jesus, Dad!” the boy yelped and then scurried off while his
father chuckled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A fight is going on inside me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dad —”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s awful, this fight —”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”— two wolves, Dad, I know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One wolf, the handsome wolf —”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dad, I think Melissa might be pregnant.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man stopped. He massaged his eyes as though what he’d heard
might have harmed his vision. He then regarded his son with a mix of
loss and sadness. Maybe some envy. He said, “I guess we know which wolf
won, don’t we?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It could’ve been either wolf, Dad. They were united on the
Melissa question.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve told Mom. She thinks Melissa should move in and we should
take the spare room until the baby’s born.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The father said, “A fight is going on inside me …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So these two wolves —” said an old man, but his young son
cut in: “I love you, Dad!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No one ever wants my wisdom,” the old man barked. At that, his
much-younger wife, Lupe, walked in with a platter. She was radiant. This
was his third marriage, and after two prior, staggering shots at bliss
and a dozen years in a Twelve Step program, he thought he’d finally
gotten his shit together. The boy was their only child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said, “I’ve got nachos! Has the game started?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dad was going to talk about his wolves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, good,” said Lupe, who’d met the old man when they’d both
volunteered during the last Democratic election and had found themselves
serendipitously stranded in an elevator one night while canvassing an
upscale apartment building. “Well, wolves love nachos. Happy Father’s
Day, honey.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everyone knows wolves love nachos,” the old man growled. He
sampled one. Chipot-olé! And she’d found his favorite queso Oaxaca. He
felt full. Whole. He wolfed them down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Riffs in the key of Two Wolves &amp;hellip;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Jazz</title><link href="/poems/2006/11/01/for-jazz.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Jazz" /><published>2006-11-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2006-11-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/poems/2006/11/01/for-jazz</id><content type="html" xml:base="/poems/2006/11/01/for-jazz.html">&lt;p&gt;I ride, Night Train, down Lankershim, 
in black boots and leather, and 
shooting Knob Creek with riders 
telling history in pictures 
etched permanent on proven arms. 
But there is a history I keep of you, 
of what you’ve done to me in those dark rooms, 
with liquor in a glass, and liquid changes 
spilling out a front door, filling 
for a moment the street with your loud 
cut-time easy laugh that sounds, God 
exactly like her, exactly like another round, 
exactly like tonight – 
you know, whatever I want, or 
whatever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your own sweet way you improvise&lt;br /&gt;
inside me from outside, with hands and fingers&lt;br /&gt;
pressing on strings, lips pressing, shaping,&lt;br /&gt;
playing my favorite things, valves clatter,&lt;br /&gt;
making air a messenger that sings.&lt;br /&gt;
I was yours then, I am now, tonight,&lt;br /&gt;
in any La Ve Lee or Blue Note,&lt;br /&gt;
you take me any way you want, slow, down,&lt;br /&gt;
cut, in a minor key, or any two five&lt;br /&gt;
one giant step cycle, roaring down Sunset&lt;br /&gt;
up at dawn, hours since the last shot,&lt;br /&gt;
an hour since the last fuck you but you’re&lt;br /&gt;
still in my head and that’s the history&lt;br /&gt;
you make in me, etched in dreams an endless&lt;br /&gt;
solo break that has changed the way I everything.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In your own sweet way you improvise inside me from outside, with hands and fingers pressing on strings, lips pressing, shaping, playing my favorite things, valves clatter, making air a messenger that sings &amp;hellip;</summary></entry></feed>